Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1945
  - Army Tests - History 133 (Box 8, Folder 219)
    - 1. List of Raw Scores & Distribution of Raw Scores for Preprofessional Term 3, 26-Jun-44
    - 2. Basic Phase Curriculum BE-1 grade sheets for Terms I-III - includes precentile conversion tables
    - 3. Achievement Test scores.
    - 4. Absence reports & list of trainees of Jewish faith.
  - Assistants - Communication (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - 1. Correspondence with instructions on various matters on ASTP assistants from [Savelle], 1 Nov 1943-23 Mar 1944
  - Comments on ASTP History course & Army Achievement Test (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - 1. Criticism reports on History 31 - 71, exams, etc., 1944-45
  - Coordinator's Office - Messrs. Harriman, Sensabaugh, Johnson (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - 1. Schedule of exams, 13-Dec-45
    - 2. Memo to ASTP instructors re time schedule for reports, scheduling of exams, etc., 1944-45
  - Correspondence - General (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - 1. Mainly correspondence with book companies, 28 Sep 1943-17 Jul 1945
  - Correspondence - University (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - 1. Basic Curriculum B-65 as a replacement.
    - 2. ASTP prospects for summer quarter.
    - 3. Memo to Miss Gay, History Dept. from M.J. Cody, Registrar's Office.
    - 4. Memo to Curricula Directors & Dept. Heads from Alvin C. Eurich with report on time devoted to ADTP.
    - 5. Memo from Edgar E. Robinson re memo concerning instructional costs of program & report on instruction time in program, 18-Oct-44
    - 6. History Inter-Dept. correspondence. Includes names of Gay, Sensabaugh, W.H. Johnson, Mitchel, Bailey, Robinson, Savelle. All pertaining to ASTP sections & courses. Includes some statistics & list of some of the professors & their educational background. Also memo on tentative training strength & procedures for Basic I,II & III, 31 Aug 1943-11 Sep 1944
  - Curriculum, Basic Phase (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - 1. History 73 Course Objectives, Contents & Procedures.
    - 2. Basic Curriculum B-65.
    - 3. History 72 - summer schedule, 1945
    - 4. History 72 Course Objectives, Contents & Procedures.
    - 5. History 31 - 71, course outline.
    - 6. College Training Program (Aircrew).
    - 7. Outline for History 133.
    - 8. Reserve Curricula Introduction Report (Georg Knoles), 25-Apr-44
    - 9. Curricula N-10, N-20, B-60 -, 25-Apr-44
    - 10. Introductory Curriculum N-30, 8-Aug-44
    - 11. List of textbooks & instructional meterial used in ASTP.
    - 12. Memorandum - Evaluation of Curricula.
    - 13. History 11-61 - Selection of paper topics for the course.
    - 14. Teacher's Manual for Higher American Citizen ship Charts, A Teacher's Manual for the Sanford-Grady American History Maps, Both for History 133., 1930, 1942
  - History for the Army (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - 1. Objectives & procedures & content of History 11-61 (America in World Affairs).
    - 2. Circular on Curricula N-10, N-20 & B-60, 25-Apr-44
  - Miscellaneous - ASTP (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - 1. Corrected rosters for Cycle I, 14-Dec-45
    - 2. Report on Time Devoted to ASTP by Gay & Bouret.
    - 3. Spring quarter & winter quarter scheduling sheets.
    - 4. Brief outline of History 31a.
    - 5. History 133 schedule of sections, 2-Feb-44
    - 6. Scheduling plans for M. Savelle:, 14 Dec 1943, 22, 25, 27 Mar 1944, 4, & Apr 1944
    - 7. Memo re receipt of maps.
    - 8. Revised University calendar to co-ordinate University & ASTP, autumn-summer, 1944
    - 9. Autumn schedule for Bailey.
    - 10. Various schedules for sections including schedules for Moule & Gay.
    - 11. Quarterly budgets for instruction of AST units: (7) (4), 1 Oct 1943, 29 Jan 1944, 8 May 1944
    - 12. Holograph page of supplies & time list, winter 1944
    - 13. Summer quarter 1943 list of assistants & instructors & costs.
    - 14. Cost analysis for History 133, 28-Sep-43
    - 15. Forms for additional requirements of AST textbooks, 10 Jan-30 Jun 1944
    - 16. Holograph notes.
    - 17. Report on ASTP 705 - Historical Geography of France.
    - 18. Suggestions for using AST achievement test results.
  - Examinations, History 11-61, 121a, 133, Summer 1944 - (Box 9, Folder 228)
  - Examinations, History 31-71, Winter 1944-45 - (Box 9, Folder 229)
  - Examinations, History 31-71, Autumn 1943-44 - (Box 9, Folder 230)
  - Examinations, History 72, Term I, Summer 1945 - (Box 9, Folder 231)
  - Examinations, History 73, Term II, Autumn 1945 - (Box 9, Folder 232)
  - Examinations, History 133, Terms I-III. Examination Schedules, Preprofessional Unit., Spring 1944 - (Box 9, Folder 233)
  - Examinations, History 133, Terms I-III, Winter 1944 - (Box 9, Folder 234)
  - Examinations, Autumn 1943 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    Review questions for History 133.
  - Instructors - Communications (Box 9, Folder 236)
    Correspondence to and between instructors, 4 Oct. 1943 - 6 July 1945.
  - Answer Keys (could not be matched with exams in folders 228-235) (Box 9, Folder 237)
  - Questionnaires (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - 1. 1 detailed questionnaire Information on Courses in American History & Civics in California 4 year & Senior High Schools.
    - 2. Ca. 60 questionnaires re educational background of the trainees, U.S. History courses taken in high school & what aspects of American history before 1900 they wish to have reviewed.
    - 3. Questionnaires for the trainees asking educational background, history courses taken, history books read.
  - Syllabi (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - 1. History 11-61 -, Summer 1944
    - 2. History 31-71 -, Winter 1945
    - 3. History 31-71 -, Autumn 1944
    - 4. History 72 -, Summer 1945
    - 5. History 73 -, Autumn 1945
    - 6. History 133 - (Terms II & III); (Terms I-III); (Terms I-III); and (Term II)., Summer 1944 Spring 1944 Winter 1944 Autumn 1943
  - Trainee - Authorized Absence Reports (Box 9, Folder 240)
    Contents of folder destroyed - remainder kept as sample.
  - Grade Sheets, Summer 1943 - Autumn 1945 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    Representative grade sheets from each quarter between above dates. Includes 8 weeks reports & end quarter reports. Mainly History 133, some Curriculum BE-1, History 31 & History 73.
  - Class Roll Books, Summer 1943-Autumn 1945 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    Representatives kept from each quarter
- Files of Prof. Gordon Craig, 1962-1974
  - Arms Control
    - Lectures (4), 1970-71 (Box 10, Folder 243)
    - Text, interim 1974 edition, for winter 1975 course. (Box 10, Folder 244)
    - Legislative history of the Jackson amendment, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 245)
    - Textbook, Ch. I-IX. [for the Stanford Materials, Aug 1974, Aug 26-30, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Textbook, Ch. X-XV. [see explanation, Folder 246.], Aug 1974 (Box 10, Folder 247)
    - Lectures (3), 1971 (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - Lectures (2), 1971 (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - Lectures (1), 1971 (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - Armaments, NATO, Helsinki, Vienna, etc., 1973 (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - Text: Draft, Ch. I, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - Text: Prelim. draft, Ch. I, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 253)
    - Text: Prelim. draft, Ch. II, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 254)
    - Text: Prelim. draft, Ch. III, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 255)
    - Text: Prelim, draft, Ch. IV, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - Ford Foundation Proposal, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - Committees
    - Committee on Relations Among Nations, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - Committee on Relations Among Nations, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - Committees on International Relations, (incl. material re. various international relations committees, 1968 1964-69 (Box 11, Folder 260)
    - International Relations Committee: Course and reading lists, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 261)
    - International Relations Committee:, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 262a)
    - International Relations Committee:, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 262b)
    - International Relations Committee:, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 262c)
    - International Relations Committee: Report, May-69 (Box 12, Folder 263)
    - International Relations Committee:, 1972-74 (Box 12, Folder 264)
    - CRIS (Center for Research in International Studies): Search Committee, 1972-73 (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - CIR/CRIS, (Committee on International Relations/Center for Research in International Studies), 1970-71 (Box 13, Folder 266)
    - CRIS, Jan-Jun 1972 (Box 13, Folder 267)
    - CRIS, Jun 1972-Feb 1974 (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - General Studies, Comm. on, [incl. minutes], 1966 (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - General Studies, Comm. on, [incl. minutes], 1964-65 (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - General Studies, Comm. on, [incl. minutes], 1962-63 (Box 14, Folder 271)
    - General Studies, Comm. on, [incl. minutes], 1963-64 (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - Faculty Self-Discipline, Floor Management Committee, 1970-72 (Box 13, Folder 273)
    - Faculty Self-Discipline, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 274)
    - Faculty Self-Discipline Code, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 275)
    - AAUP (American Association of University Professors): Commission on Faculty Self-Discipline, 1969-70 (Box 15, Folder 276)
    - AAUP Report on Government of University, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 277)
- General Departmental Files, 1952-1974
  Boxes 16 through 21 are restricted; consult the University Archivist for access.
  - Adams, James D. [Knoles], 1971-72 (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - Advisees, [Craig], 1972-74 (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - Africa - History; Joint Appointment, [Wright, Knoles], 1963-65 (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - African Studies, [Potter], 1967-68 (Box 16, Folder 281)
  - Afro-American History, [Knoles], 1968-70 (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - Afro-American Studies, [Knoles], 1968-69 (Box 16, Folder 283)
  - AHA Meeting (American Historical Assn.), [Potter], 1966 (Box 16, Folder 284)
  - Americanist, [Potter, Knoles], 1971-72 (Box 16, Folder 285)
  - Americanist - Diplomatic, [Potter], 1966 (Box 16, Folder 286)
  - Americanist - General, [Potter], 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 287)
  - Americanist - Inactive, [Potter], 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 288)
  - Americanist - Kennedy, [Potter], 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 289)
  - Americanist - Pomeroy, [Potter], 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 290)
  - BAP (Budget Adjustment Program), [General], 1970-71 (Box 16, Folder 291)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 16, Folder 292)
  - China Prospects, [Smith, Knoles], 1968-69 (Box 16, Folder 293)
  - Committee on International Studies, [Potter], 1965-67 (Box 16, Folder 294)
  - Communications to Staff, [Potter], 1965-67 (Box 16, Folder 295)
  - Comparative History, [Potter], 1966-67 (Box 16, Folder 296)
  - Courses and Degrees, [Potter], 1967-68 (Box 17, Folder 297)
  - Course Schedule, [General], 1962-65 (Box 17, Folder 298)
  - Courses Scheduled, [General], 1965-68 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Course Syllabuses, [General], 1965-66 (Box 17, Folder 300)
  - Dawson, Philip, [Knoles] Includes articles., 1969-70 (Box 17, Folder 301)
  - Dean, Benjamin Douglass, Fund (Institute of American History), [Knoles], 1966-72 (Box 17, Folder 302)
  - Degree Requirements, [Knoles], 1952-69 (Box 17, Folder 303)
  - Dept. Meetings, [Knoles] Includes minutes., 1968-69 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Dept. organization, [Knoles], 1968-72 (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - Departmental Rosters, [Potter], 1967-68 (Box 17, Folder 306)
  - East Asia, [General], 1960-65 (Box 17, Folder 307)
  - East Asian Appointment, [General], 1966-69 (Box 17, Folder 308)
  - East Asian Studies, [General], 1966-69 (Box 17, Folder 309)
  - East European Studies, [General], 1968 (Box 17, Folder 310)
  - European Appt., [General], 1966-67 (Box 17, Folder 311)
  - Fellowship Committee Files [General] (Box 18, Folder 312)
  - Fellowships, [General], 1962-65 (Box 18, Folder 313)
  - Freshman Seminars, [Potter], 1965-68 (Box 18, Folder 314)
  - General Studies, [Potter], 1966-68 (Box 18, Folder 315)
  - Gifts, [Potter-Knoles], 1966-72 (Box 18, Folder 316)
  - Graduate Admissions, [Knoles], 1965-69 (Box 18, Folder 317)
  - Grad. Admissions, [Potter-Knoles], 1967-68 (Box 18, Folder 318)
  - Grad. Admissions - Support, [Knoles], 1968-72 (Box 18, Folder 319)
  - Guest Lecturers, [Knoles], 1968-71 (Box 19, Folder 320)
  - History 200 (D. Kennedy), [Knoles], 1968-69 (Box 19, Folder 321)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 322)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 323)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 324)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 325)
  - Honors Program, [Potter], 1966-70 (Box 19, Folder 326)
  - Hoover Institute, [Potter-Knoles], 1966-70 (Box 19, Folder 327)
  - Housekeeping Items, [General], 1959-69 (Box 19, Folder 328)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 329)
  - Humanities and Sciences, [Potter], 1965-68 (Box 19, Folder 330)
  - Institute of American History - Budget, [General], 1961-70 (Box 19, Folder 331)
  - Instructional Costs, [General], 1962-67 (Box 19, Folder 332)
  - Johnson, Wesley, [Knoles], 1968-71 (Box 19, Folder 333)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 19, Folder 334)
  - Grad. Admissions and Fellowships, Assistantships, [Wright], 1958-64 (Box 20, Folder 335)
  - Grad. Assistants, T.A.S., and Work-Study, [Potter-Knoles], 1966-69 (Box 20, Folder 336)
  - Graduate Curriculum, [Potter], 1966 (Box 20, Folder 337)
  - Graduate Students, [Knoles-Wright], 1962-65 (Box 20, Folder 338)
  - Graduate Students. Teaching, [Knoles], 1968 (Box 20, Folder 339)
  - Latin America, [Wright-Knoles], 1962-64 (Box 20, Folder 340)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 20, Folder 341)
  - Library, [General], 1962-65 (Box 20, Folder 342)
  - Library: Old File, [General], 1957-63 (Box 20, Folder 343)
  - Mexican-American Studies, [Knoles], 1969-70 (Box 20, Folder 344)
  - Modern France, [Knoles], 1970 (Box 20, Folder 345)
  - New Appointments, General, [General], 1958-65 (Box 20, Folder 346)
  - Potter, David, [Knoles] Includes memorial resolution, obituaries., 1970-72 (Box 20, Folder 347)
  - Rhodes James, Robert, [Potter], 1966-68 (Box 21, Folder 348)
  - Rosenberg, John, [Potter], 1968 (Box 21, Folder 349)
  - Sabbaticals and Leaves, [Wright], 1960-65 (Box 21, Folder 350)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 21, Folder 351)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 21, Folder 352)
  - Spingarn, Stephen, [Potter], 1966-68 (Box 21, Folder 353)
  - Summer School - old file, [Wright], 1958-63 (Box 21, Folder 354)
  - Summer Session, [Potter], 1966 (Box 21, Folder 355)
  - Telephone, [Potter], 1967 (Box 21, Folder 356)
  - [File returned to History Department 10/75.] (Box 21, Folder 357)
  - Toynbee, Arnold, [Potter], 1967 (Box 21, Folder 358)
  - Travel, [Wright], 1961-65 (Box 21, Folder 359)
  - Western Civilization, [Knoles], 1963-69 (Box 21, Folder 360)
  - Western Civilization, [Knoles], 1968-71 (Box 21, Folder 361)
  - Woodrow Wilsons, [Knoles], 1965-70 (Box 21, Folder 362)